<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marketing Luxury Real Estate Consulting Video Blog with Michael LaFido</title>
    <description>A Video Blog about Marketing Luxury Listings ; its industry, and the people working in it. Whether you're just starting out, aspiring to begin, or been working in the field for a few years, tune in to get updates, tips, tricks and more!</description>
    <link>luxeredefined.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="luxeredefined.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 16:15:49 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 16:15:49 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reflecting on Our Progress in 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HONuDq-psS8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hosted 13 live Luxury Listing Specialists Certification classes this past year, from the east coast to down south, and even north to Canada. Overall, we had agents from 28 states represented. &lt;strong&gt;With all our training and activities this past year, we&lt;br /&gt;definitely racked up some frequent flyer miles.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, there were a few other points from 2018 that I’m excited to share with you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We formed a strategic alliance with “Who’s Who in Luxury Real Estate?”, and we were fortunate enough to present at both of their conferences.  For more information, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.LuxuryRealEstate.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.LuxuryRealEstate.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In just the second half of the year, we certified 155 RE/MAX INTEGRA agents get LUXE certified. There are over 40,000 agents in total at RE/MAX INTEGRA. They have already booked us for two more live certification classes in 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We gave away over $50,000 in LUXE scholarships in 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We were also recognized by the International Property Awards as not only one of the best consulting businesses for agents looking to sell high-end properties in the United States,  but also globally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For us at the Luxury Listing Specialists, it was truly a great year, and we hope that yours was just as momentous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We were also recognized as not only one of the best consulting businesses for agents looking to sell high-end properties in the nation but also globally.%20luxeredefined.com/reflecting-on-our-progress-in-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We were also recognized as not only one of the best consulting businesses for agents looking to sell high-end properties in the nation but also globally.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. Otherwise, for some great content, check out our Luxury Listing podcasts at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.LuxuryListingPodcast.com&quot;&gt;www.LuxuryListingPodcast.com&lt;/a&gt;. Until then, like I always say: Prove them wrong!   Continue to raise the bar, and remember—it’s not the market, it’s the marketing. Here’s to another great year ahead in 2019!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 02:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/reflecting-on-our-progress-in-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/reflecting-on-our-progress-in-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Business Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Do You Need To Start Or Differentiate Your Luxury Division?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v0y_jNQeqOM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to increase the number of high-end and luxury transactions for your office, team, or individual sales then having a strong luxury division is not optional.  What does a strong, dedicated luxury division look like, though?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old way of starting, or unfortunately many brokers’ current luxury divisions (which many franchises still ascribe to), is to just have a different logo for their luxury division or a luxury sign for their offices. That’s not a luxury division and that doesn’t benefit the agents or the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new way and true luxury division involves: better training and resources, &lt;strong&gt;better-qualified agents, a dedicated luxury division website with only luxury listings, and, perhaps, a prerequisite for agents to quality to be listed as a luxury agent in your office.  Many of our clients require their agents have the Luxury Listing Specialist Certification (LUXE)&lt;/strong&gt; or another strong luxury certification before that agent can be listed on their luxury division directory or website. That’s what a strong luxury division is all about—giving your agents an advantage through better training and resources over other agents and brokerages in your area when selling high-end properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=That’s what a strong luxury division is all about—giving your agents an advantage over other firms in your area when selling high-end properties.%20luxeredefined.com/what-do-you-need-to-start-or-differentiate-your-luxury-division.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“That’s what a strong luxury division is all about—giving your agents an advantage over other firms in your area when selling high-end properties.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like additional information on how we can help you launch a luxury division or strengthen your luxury division, shoot us an email or give us a call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this topic or you have a topic in mind you’d like to see me discuss in a future video, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to speak to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 03:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/what-do-you-need-to-start-or-differentiate-your-luxury-division.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/what-do-you-need-to-start-or-differentiate-your-luxury-division.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Up to the Challenge of Spreading Positivity This Holiday Season?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CjA4T9iYpwk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leaves are changing, the holidays are approaching, and Thanksgiving is just around the corner. Right now is the perfect time to reflect on what you’re thankful for. That said, I would also encourage you to reflect on the trials you’ve faced this year and those you anticipate moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as you consider these challenges, don’t allow the opinions of those who would say you can’t overcome them drag you down. Prove naysayers wrong. Don’t let past obstacles deter you from future successes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t let past obstacles deter you from future successes.%20luxeredefined.com/are-you-up-to-the-challenge-of-spreading-positivity-this-holiday-season.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t let past obstacles deter you from future successes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;while you strive to improve your own lives, do the same for those around you.&lt;/strong&gt; Make someone’s day whenever you have the chance. Your continued support has certainly been a positive force in my life, and today I’d like to challenge you to continue spreading positivity wherever and however you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much hostility and negativity pervading our current culture. Let this holiday season be a reminder that we are all humans. &lt;strong&gt;Whatever differences we may have, we should all strive to build one another up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, I’d like to thank you on behalf of my entire team for the great year we’ve had. May your holiday season be filled with joy and positivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me or my team, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 23:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/are-you-up-to-the-challenge-of-spreading-positivity-this-holiday-season.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/are-you-up-to-the-challenge-of-spreading-positivity-this-holiday-season.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Double Your Real Estate Income in 90 Days?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PvgQRdGMuM4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many agents are looking for that magic pill. However, success comes down to blocking and tackling those x’s and o’s. These are the three fastest ways you can double your income in the next 90 days as an agent or team leader:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Increase the average sale price of a home you represent.&lt;/strong&gt; I think this is the easiest strategy. The goal for any agent that goes through our luxury listing specialist certification is to increase their average sale price by 30% in a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Be more profitable per transaction.&lt;/strong&gt; This could include cutting away some fat from your marketing budget with methods that aren’t working. This could also include protecting your fee. If you bring enough value to the table, you shouldn’t have to compete by discounting what you charge. If you get really good at this and get your clients a higher list-to-sale ratio, you might be able to charge more than whatever the going rate is in your market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Increase your conversion rate.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re converting five out of 10 listing appointments right now, that would put you in the hall of fame in the major leagues. However, in real estate, you should be doing much better than that. The more we can increase your conversion rate, the more listings you’ll get, and the more likely you are to get more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The more you can increase your conversion rate, the more listings you’ll get.%20luxeredefined.com/how-can-you-double-your-real-estate-income-in-90-days.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The more you can increase your conversion rate, the more listings you’ll get.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about any of these strategies or anything else about luxury real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 11:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/how-can-you-double-your-real-estate-income-in-90-days.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/how-can-you-double-your-real-estate-income-in-90-days.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Need to Promote a High-End or Luxury Home? Try Event-Based Marketing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XNxEYnKb-Wk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes time to list a high-end or luxury property, event-based marketing is an extremely effective selling strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-end homes, defined as those valued at least two times the average sales price, and luxury homes, defined as those valued at least three times the average sales price, tend to be highly unique. With that being said, the marketing techniques one might use for a listing in a lower price range may not be sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wine and cheese tastings or broker open houses are fine, generally speaking, but for the kinds of properties we’re discussing today, an invite-only event may be even better.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, one amazing property currently on the market in Scottsdale, Arizona, for just over $6.5 million. The agents working on this listing, who I’ve been coaching for the last several months, have hosted a couple of events at the property so far. One of these events was an invite-only, two-day “Freedom Summit,” which we held on September 28 and September 29.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The primary benefit of event-based marketing is its superlative ability to draw exposure.%20luxeredefined.com/need-to-promote-a-high-end-or-luxury-home-try-event-based-marketing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The primary benefit of event-based marketing is its superlative ability to draw exposure.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is a prime example of event-based marketing. The 90 agents who attended and the owner of the property mutually benefited from this educational summit, which was also attended by a number of preferred vendors and sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Events of this calibur, though, do require a higher level of planning than what might be the case for an average open house.&lt;/strong&gt; In addition to orchestrating the event itself, the property’s owner will also need to guard themselves against liability and security concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary benefit of event-based marketing is its superlative ability to draw exposure. The agents who attend will benefit from the networking opportunity the event provides, and the seller will also benefit from the buyer interest that is generated, in turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 02:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/need-to-promote-a-high-end-or-luxury-home-try-event-based-marketing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/need-to-promote-a-high-end-or-luxury-home-try-event-based-marketing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Never Talk Price on a Luxury Listing Appointment</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9RbgFuAR8Xw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go on a listing appointment for a unique luxury property that’s not located in a cookie-cutter neighborhood, &lt;strong&gt;never talk price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old way to go on a listing appointment meant bringing along your CMA, but I don’t recommend doing this because you haven’t even walked through the home yet. I always tell sellers that if they’re interviewing an agent who comes to their listing appointment with a CMA, they probably won’t be able to evaluate and price their home for that very reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, &lt;strong&gt;your goal for that first listing appointment should be to walk through the home and get a sense of its updates, floor plan, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;, so you can get back to the seller afterward with your suggested market price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new way of doing things, and one that we recommend, is to &lt;strong&gt;b&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ring along a “market analysis report” (we also refer to it as a “luxury snapshot”) to the listing appointment instead of a CMA.&lt;/strong&gt; This market analysis report (or MAR) details comparable luxury homes that are also on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You’ll turn off many luxury sellers if you come to a listing appointment prepared with a price without even having walked through the home first.%20luxeredefined.com/never-talk-price-on-a-luxury-listing-appointment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You’ll turn off many luxury sellers if you come to a listing appointment prepared with a price without even having walked through the home first.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going on a listing appointment for a luxury listing that is located in a cookie-cutter neighborhood where there are a lot of similar comps, go ahead and bring a CMA. Otherwise, you’ll turn off many luxury sellers if you come to a listing appointment prepared with a price without even having walked through the home first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So remember, differentiate yourself from the competition and let sellers know that if they talk to an agent who comes to their listing appointment with a CMA, they should show them the door. It’s also important that you know your numbers–we define “luxury price” as any price that’s 3x higher than the average sale price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this topic or there’s anything I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to call or email me anytime. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 02:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/never-talk-price-on-a-luxury-listing-appointment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/never-talk-price-on-a-luxury-listing-appointment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Overcome the Difficulties of Pricing High-End Homes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Ohg4qfU3HA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luxury homes, defined as those which are at least three times the average sales price for a given market, can be difficult to price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is the case with any real estate listing, it’s important not to rely on Zillow or other online estimates when determining home value. &lt;strong&gt;Virtual tools like these may be adequate for pricing properties in cookie-cutter neighborhoods, but they should otherwise be avoided.&lt;/strong&gt; High-end properties require more sophisticated methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strategy you use to determine home value should reflect the property you’re working with. For example, a comparative market analysis may be effective in some circumstances, but will often be insufficient when pricing a luxury home. This is because comparative market analyses rely on data from comparable properties, and so luxury properties are often too unique for this to be a viable strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The strategy you use to determine home value should reflect the property you’re working with.%20luxeredefined.com/how-to-overcome-the-difficulties-of-pricing-high-end-homes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The strategy you use to determine home value should reflect the property you’re working with.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if not by using a comparative market analysis, what is the best way for an agent to price a luxury home? First, &lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;o not prepare a pricing estimate ahead of the listing appointment.&lt;/strong&gt; Instead, let the seller know that, given the highly customized nature of their home, you wanted to examine the property in-person before passing judgment on its value. That said, don’t show up empty-handed. Come prepared to the listing appointment with a market analysis report (MAR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Market analysis reports essentially provide a snapshot of how other luxury homes in the area are performing in the market. &lt;strong&gt;By referencing this report and ordering a private appraisal, sellers will glean a much clearer picture of their home’s true value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of this in mind, it’s also essential to remember the impact of the overall market. It’s crucial to keep market trends in mind when pricing a luxury home, just as you would for any other property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/pendulum-swing-edit-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 23:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/how-to-overcome-the-difficulties-of-pricing-high-end-homes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/how-to-overcome-the-difficulties-of-pricing-high-end-homes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sellers: Don't Make This Common Mistake</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EmgU5u4kITA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, we’re in the prime selling season here in Chicago. But, if you have plans to put your home on the market, there is one mistake you must avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many sellers hire the agent who estimates the highest price for their home.&lt;/strong&gt; If one agent tells them they should list for $550,000 and another tells them they should list for $500,000, most sellers will, unfortunately, choose the agent who gave that higher price. However, this is actually the No.1 listing mistake a seller could make in our market. The market, not your agent, dictates price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, sellers should hire an agent they like and trust. They should hire an agent with whom they have a good rapport and who has a proven marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of working with the right agent, it’s also important to be informed about our current market. &lt;strong&gt;One of the most important things to understand is how current supply impacts the traction you’ll have as a seller in our market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A market with more than seven months of supply is a buyer’s market, a market with five or six months of supply is an even market, and a market with between one and four months of supply is a seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The market, not your agent, dictates price.%20luxeredefined.com/sellers-dont-make-this-common-mistake.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The market, not your agent, dictates price.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to gauge the market is by examining the list-to-sale price ratio in your price range. This is important because while your area might be a seller’s market, your specific price range could still be favoring buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, the spring market is a great time to sell. So &lt;strong&gt;if you have been thinking of listing, now is the time to do so.&lt;/strong&gt; I recommend you start interviewing agents as soon as possible. Also, if your home is already on the market, the next 90 days are vital. You should ideally have your home under contract before July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, would like more information, or want help with your home sale, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 12:32:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/sellers-dont-make-this-common-mistake.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/sellers-dont-make-this-common-mistake.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Name the 4 Price Points in Your Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ExUME-xnY_E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter where you live, there are four price points in every market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say price points, I don’t mean rental pricing—I mean the average closing price points of all home sales. &lt;strong&gt;These price points can vary within your particular market, so you need to know what they are.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first and lowest price point contains the entry-level homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second price point, or the one just above entry-level, contains the average price point homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third price point features the high-end homes. We define high-end homes as those that are worth twice as much as the average sale price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth and final price point is for the luxury homes. We define luxury homes as those that are worth three times the average sale price. It’s important to remember that luxury homes, like entry-level homes, are defined differently for each market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are four price points in any market.%20luxeredefined.com/can-you-name-the-4-price-points-in-your-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are four price points in any market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an agent and you specialize in entry-level and average price point homes, &lt;strong&gt;I suggest you diversify your real estate portfolio to include more high-end and luxury homes.&lt;/strong&gt; This is what we teach in our Luxury Listing Specialist Certification Program. Our goal is to get you to increase the average sale price of the homes you represent and make more money by working smarter, not harder. We want you to increase your income level by 30% by adding more high-end and luxury homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about knowing your price points or want to learn more about diversifying your portfolio, don’t hesitate to call or email me anytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t forget to check out our “Luxury Listing Specialist” podcast on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/luxury-listing-specialist-dominate-high-end-listings/id1203325371?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iTunes &lt;/a&gt;or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/michael-lafido/luxury-listing-specialist-wmichael-lafido&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;. If you’d like more information or want a shot at winning some free prizes, text “LUXE” to 72000.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 23:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/can-you-name-the-4-price-points-in-your-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/can-you-name-the-4-price-points-in-your-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The New Approach to Selling Your Luxury Listings</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3YEev1slVNc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are going to talk about a different approach to getting your stale listing sold. If you have a listing that is not getting activity for whatever reason, &lt;strong&gt;there are two types of approaches that will help expedite the sale.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old approach involves going back to the agent and telling them that your seller is motivated and all offers will be considered. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The new approach is what I call the “ROS” or Reverse Offer Strategy.&lt;/strong&gt; Here is an example of how it works in action. We recently helped an owner sell their home and went back to a buyer who had seen the home about three weeks previously but had not pulled the trigger. In real estate, time is the killer of all deals, and we knew that the home was not top of mind for the buyer or their agent. &lt;strong&gt;So, we went back to these buyers and made an offer to them.&lt;/strong&gt; We ended up getting a deal together, all thanks to the ROS strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, we are helping an agent market a $6.5 million property out in Scottsdale. There are four interested parties, but a few of them have not been returning calls or texts for a while. Using the ROS strategy, we made each of these buyers an offer and are hopeful to get a deal done quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Not only do you get to control the sale price, but it also eliminates any lowball offers.%20luxeredefined.com/the-new-approach-to-selling-your-luxury-listings.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Not only do you get to control the sale price, but it also eliminates any lowball offers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is a hypothetical situation where the ROS strategy would work quite well.&lt;/strong&gt; Let’s say you have a $2 million dollar listing in a market where these homes are selling at an average of 90% of their asking price. 90% of $2 million is $1.8 million. &lt;strong&gt;You might be able to go back to the buyer and make them an offer of $1.895 million with a $25,000 bonus to the buyer’s agent if it closes by a certain date.&lt;/strong&gt; In essence, the seller will net $1.87 million, which is well above the 90% list-to-sale ratio. But how do you present this offer to the buyer’s agent? Here’s how that conversation will go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Hey there. You showed my listing previously and mentioned your client is no longer interested. Well, my client actually wants to make your client the offer and would be willing to sell the property for $1.895 million. If we can get a deal done, we would give you a $25,000 bonus on top of your commission. I wanted to let you know about this so please present it to your client and get back to us.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not bring up percentages with the buyer’s agent or buyer,&lt;/strong&gt; but make sure they know the price you are giving them is lower than your list price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the new way of doing things. If you have any questions for me or want to learn more about the reverse offer strategy, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email at any time. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/the-new-approach-to-selling-your-luxury-listings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">luxeredefined.com/the-new-approach-to-selling-your-luxury-listings.html</guid>
        
        <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
