<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Marketing Luxury Real Estate Podcast Video Blog with Michael LaFido</title>
    <link>luxeredefined.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="luxeredefined.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Marketing Luxury Group - your professional Marketing Luxury Listings Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Michael LaFido</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-01-08 16:15:49 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Michael LaFido</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>michael@marketingluxurygroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Michael LaFido</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="luxeredefined.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Marketing Luxury Listings Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Marketing Luxury Group - your professional Marketing Luxury Listings Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reflecting on Our Progress in 2018</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/reflecting-on-our-progress-in-2018.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Business Tips</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-04 02:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We hosted 13 live Luxury Listing Specialists Certification classes this past year, from the east coast to down south, and even north to Canada. Overall, we had agents from 28 states represented. With all our training and activities this past year, wedefinitely racked up some frequent flyer miles.

Beyond that, there were a few other points from 2018 that I’m excited to share with you:


  We formed a strategic alliance with “Who’s Who in Luxury Real Estate?”, and we were fortunate enough to present at both of their conferences.  For more information, visit www.LuxuryRealEstate.com
  In just the second half of the year, we certified 155 RE/MAX INTEGRA agents get LUXE certified. There are over 40,000 agents in total at RE/MAX INTEGRA. They have already booked us for two more live certification classes in 2019.
  We gave away over $50,000 in LUXE scholarships in 2018.
  We were also recognized by the International Property Awards as not only one of the best consulting businesses for agents looking to sell high-end properties in the United States,  but also globally.


For us at the Luxury Listing Specialists, it was truly a great year, and we hope that yours was just as momentous.

“We were also recognized as not only one of the best consulting businesses for agents looking to sell high-end properties in the nation but also globally.”If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. Otherwise, for some great content, check out our Luxury Listing podcasts at www.LuxuryListingPodcast.com. Until then, like I always say: Prove them wrong!   Continue to raise the bar, and remember—it’s not the market, it’s the marketing. Here’s to another great year ahead in 2019!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Before we get too far into the new year, today I think it’s a good idea to look back on the progress we made in 2018.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Before we get too far into the new year, today I think it’s a good idea to look back on the progress we made in 2018.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do You Need To Start Or Differentiate Your Luxury Division?</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/what-do-you-need-to-start-or-differentiate-your-luxury-division.html</link>
        
          <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-17 03:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking to increase the number of high-end and luxury transactions for your office, team, or individual sales then having a strong luxury division is not optional.  What does a strong, dedicated luxury division look like, though?

The old way of starting, or unfortunately many brokers’ current luxury divisions (which many franchises still ascribe to), is to just have a different logo for their luxury division or a luxury sign for their offices. That’s not a luxury division and that doesn’t benefit the agents or the consumer.

The new way and true luxury division involves: better training and resources, better-qualified agents, a dedicated luxury division website with only luxury listings, and, perhaps, a prerequisite for agents to quality to be listed as a luxury agent in your office.  Many of our clients require their agents have the Luxury Listing Specialist Certification (LUXE) or another strong luxury certification before that agent can be listed on their luxury division directory or website. That’s what a strong luxury division is all about—giving your agents an advantage through better training and resources over other agents and brokerages in your area when selling high-end properties.

“That’s what a strong luxury division is all about—giving your agents an advantage over other firms in your area when selling high-end properties.”

If you would like additional information on how we can help you launch a luxury division or strengthen your luxury division, shoot us an email or give us a call.

As always, if you have any questions about this topic or you have a topic in mind you’d like to see me discuss in a future video, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to speak to you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Maintaining a strong luxury division means having better training and resources, better-qualified agents, and a strong certification.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Maintaining a strong luxury division means having better training and resources, better-qualified agents, and a strong certification.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are You Up to the Challenge of Spreading Positivity This Holiday Season?</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/are-you-up-to-the-challenge-of-spreading-positivity-this-holiday-season.html</link>
        
          <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-19 23:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Marketing+Luxury+Group/Wishing+You+An+Amazing+Thanksgiving+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The leaves are changing, the holidays are approaching, and Thanksgiving is just around the corner. Right now is the perfect time to reflect on what you’re thankful for. That said, I would also encourage you to reflect on the trials you’ve faced this year and those you anticipate moving forward.

And as you consider these challenges, don’t allow the opinions of those who would say you can’t overcome them drag you down. Prove naysayers wrong. Don’t let past obstacles deter you from future successes.

“Don’t let past obstacles deter you from future successes.”

Also, while you strive to improve your own lives, do the same for those around you. Make someone’s day whenever you have the chance. Your continued support has certainly been a positive force in my life, and today I’d like to challenge you to continue spreading positivity wherever and however you can.

There is so much hostility and negativity pervading our current culture. Let this holiday season be a reminder that we are all humans. Whatever differences we may have, we should all strive to build one another up.

Once again, I’d like to thank you on behalf of my entire team for the great year we’ve had. May your holiday season be filled with joy and positivity.

If you have any questions for me or my team, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Marketing+Luxury+Group/Wishing+You+An+Amazing+Thanksgiving+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Marketing+Luxury+Group/Wishing+You+An+Amazing+Thanksgiving+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>This holiday season, I challenge all of you to spread positivity in your life and the lives of those around you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>This holiday season, I challenge all of you to spread positivity in your life and the lives of those around you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Double Your Real Estate Income in 90 Days?</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/how-can-you-double-your-real-estate-income-in-90-days.html</link>
        
          <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-19 11:42:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/3+Ways+To+Double+Your+Income+Within+90+Days+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Many agents are looking for that magic pill. However, success comes down to blocking and tackling those x’s and o’s. These are the three fastest ways you can double your income in the next 90 days as an agent or team leader:

1. Increase the average sale price of a home you represent. I think this is the easiest strategy. The goal for any agent that goes through our luxury listing specialist certification is to increase their average sale price by 30% in a year.

2. Be more profitable per transaction. This could include cutting away some fat from your marketing budget with methods that aren’t working. This could also include protecting your fee. If you bring enough value to the table, you shouldn’t have to compete by discounting what you charge. If you get really good at this and get your clients a higher list-to-sale ratio, you might be able to charge more than whatever the going rate is in your market.

3. Increase your conversion rate. If you’re converting five out of 10 listing appointments right now, that would put you in the hall of fame in the major leagues. However, in real estate, you should be doing much better than that. The more we can increase your conversion rate, the more listings you’ll get, and the more likely you are to get more money.

“The more you can increase your conversion rate, the more listings you’ll get.”

If you have any questions about any of these strategies or anything else about luxury real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/3+Ways+To+Double+Your+Income+Within+90+Days+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/3+Ways+To+Double+Your+Income+Within+90+Days+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are three concrete ways that you can double your real estate business in the next 90 days. Here they are.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are three concrete ways that you can double your real estate business in the next 90 days. Here they are.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Need to Promote a High-End or Luxury Home? Try Event-Based Marketing</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/need-to-promote-a-high-end-or-luxury-home-try-event-based-marketing.html</link>
        
          <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-30 02:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Event+Based+Marketing+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When it comes time to list a high-end or luxury property, event-based marketing is an extremely effective selling strategy.

High-end homes, defined as those valued at least two times the average sales price, and luxury homes, defined as those valued at least three times the average sales price, tend to be highly unique. With that being said, the marketing techniques one might use for a listing in a lower price range may not be sufficient.

Wine and cheese tastings or broker open houses are fine, generally speaking, but for the kinds of properties we’re discussing today, an invite-only event may be even better.

Take, for example, one amazing property currently on the market in Scottsdale, Arizona, for just over $6.5 million. The agents working on this listing, who I’ve been coaching for the last several months, have hosted a couple of events at the property so far. One of these events was an invite-only, two-day “Freedom Summit,” which we held on September 28 and September 29.

“The primary benefit of event-based marketing is its superlative ability to draw exposure.”

This event is a prime example of event-based marketing. The 90 agents who attended and the owner of the property mutually benefited from this educational summit, which was also attended by a number of preferred vendors and sponsors.

Events of this calibur, though, do require a higher level of planning than what might be the case for an average open house. In addition to orchestrating the event itself, the property’s owner will also need to guard themselves against liability and security concerns.

The primary benefit of event-based marketing is its superlative ability to draw exposure. The agents who attend will benefit from the networking opportunity the event provides, and the seller will also benefit from the buyer interest that is generated, in turn.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Event+Based+Marketing+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Event+Based+Marketing+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Event-based marketing is an excellent way to promote high-end and luxury properties, and today we’ll explain why this is the case.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Event-based marketing is an excellent way to promote high-end and luxury properties, and today we’ll explain why this is the case.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Never Talk Price on a Luxury Listing Appointment</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/never-talk-price-on-a-luxury-listing-appointment.html</link>
        
          <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-08 02:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/What+You+Need+To+Price+A+Luxury+Home+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you go on a listing appointment for a unique luxury property that’s not located in a cookie-cutter neighborhood, never talk price.

The old way to go on a listing appointment meant bringing along your CMA, but I don’t recommend doing this because you haven’t even walked through the home yet. I always tell sellers that if they’re interviewing an agent who comes to their listing appointment with a CMA, they probably won’t be able to evaluate and price their home for that very reason.

Ideally, your goal for that first listing appointment should be to walk through the home and get a sense of its updates, floor plan, etc., so you can get back to the seller afterward with your suggested market price.

The new way of doing things, and one that we recommend, is to bring along a “market analysis report” (we also refer to it as a “luxury snapshot”) to the listing appointment instead of a CMA. This market analysis report (or MAR) details comparable luxury homes that are also on the market.

“You’ll turn off many luxury sellers if you come to a listing appointment prepared with a price without even having walked through the home first.”

If you’re going on a listing appointment for a luxury listing that is located in a cookie-cutter neighborhood where there are a lot of similar comps, go ahead and bring a CMA. Otherwise, you’ll turn off many luxury sellers if you come to a listing appointment prepared with a price without even having walked through the home first.

So remember, differentiate yourself from the competition and let sellers know that if they talk to an agent who comes to their listing appointment with a CMA, they should show them the door. It’s also important that you know your numbers–we define “luxury price” as any price that’s 3x higher than the average sale price.

As always, if you have any questions about this topic or there’s anything I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to call or email me anytime. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/What+You+Need+To+Price+A+Luxury+Home+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/What+You+Need+To+Price+A+Luxury+Home+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When you go on a luxury listing appointment, don’t bring along a CMA. Here’s what we recommend you do instead.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When you go on a luxury listing appointment, don’t bring along a CMA. Here’s what we recommend you do instead.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Overcome the Difficulties of Pricing High-End Homes</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/how-to-overcome-the-difficulties-of-pricing-high-end-homes.html</link>
        
          <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-19 23:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Pricing+Your+Luxury+Home+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Luxury homes, defined as those which are at least three times the average sales price for a given market, can be difficult to price.

As is the case with any real estate listing, it’s important not to rely on Zillow or other online estimates when determining home value. Virtual tools like these may be adequate for pricing properties in cookie-cutter neighborhoods, but they should otherwise be avoided. High-end properties require more sophisticated methods.

The strategy you use to determine home value should reflect the property you’re working with. For example, a comparative market analysis may be effective in some circumstances, but will often be insufficient when pricing a luxury home. This is because comparative market analyses rely on data from comparable properties, and so luxury properties are often too unique for this to be a viable strategy.

“The strategy you use to determine home value should reflect the property you’re working with.”

So, if not by using a comparative market analysis, what is the best way for an agent to price a luxury home? First, do not prepare a pricing estimate ahead of the listing appointment. Instead, let the seller know that, given the highly customized nature of their home, you wanted to examine the property in-person before passing judgment on its value. That said, don’t show up empty-handed. Come prepared to the listing appointment with a market analysis report (MAR).

Market analysis reports essentially provide a snapshot of how other luxury homes in the area are performing in the market. By referencing this report and ordering a private appraisal, sellers will glean a much clearer picture of their home’s true value.

With all of this in mind, it’s also essential to remember the impact of the overall market. It’s crucial to keep market trends in mind when pricing a luxury home, just as you would for any other property.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.


</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Pricing+Your+Luxury+Home+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Pricing+Your+Luxury+Home+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is the right way to price a luxury property? Let’s discuss a few key strategies and how they differ from what may be utilized within other price points.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is the right way to price a luxury property? Let’s discuss a few key strategies and how they differ from what may be utilized within other price points.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Sellers: Don't Make This Common Mistake</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/sellers-dont-make-this-common-mistake.html</link>
        
          <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-11 12:32:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/The+Number+One+Mistake+Sellers+Make+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Right now, we’re in the prime selling season here in Chicago. But, if you have plans to put your home on the market, there is one mistake you must avoid.

Many sellers hire the agent who estimates the highest price for their home. If one agent tells them they should list for $550,000 and another tells them they should list for $500,000, most sellers will, unfortunately, choose the agent who gave that higher price. However, this is actually the No.1 listing mistake a seller could make in our market. The market, not your agent, dictates price.

Instead, sellers should hire an agent they like and trust. They should hire an agent with whom they have a good rapport and who has a proven marketing strategy.

On top of working with the right agent, it’s also important to be informed about our current market. One of the most important things to understand is how current supply impacts the traction you’ll have as a seller in our market.

A market with more than seven months of supply is a buyer’s market, a market with five or six months of supply is an even market, and a market with between one and four months of supply is a seller’s market.

“The market, not your agent, dictates price.”

Another way to gauge the market is by examining the list-to-sale price ratio in your price range. This is important because while your area might be a seller’s market, your specific price range could still be favoring buyers.

In general, the spring market is a great time to sell. So if you have been thinking of listing, now is the time to do so. I recommend you start interviewing agents as soon as possible. Also, if your home is already on the market, the next 90 days are vital. You should ideally have your home under contract before July.

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or want help with your home sale, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/The+Number+One+Mistake+Sellers+Make+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/The+Number+One+Mistake+Sellers+Make+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s going on in today’s market and how are these current conditions affecting sellers? Let’s go over a few key points.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s going on in today’s market and how are these current conditions affecting sellers? Let’s go over a few key points.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can You Name the 4 Price Points in Your Market?</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/can-you-name-the-4-price-points-in-your-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-28 23:58:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/The+4+Price+Points+Of+Real+Estate+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

No matter where you live, there are four price points in every market.

When I say price points, I don’t mean rental pricing—I mean the average closing price points of all home sales. These price points can vary within your particular market, so you need to know what they are.

The first and lowest price point contains the entry-level homes.

The second price point, or the one just above entry-level, contains the average price point homes.

The third price point features the high-end homes. We define high-end homes as those that are worth twice as much as the average sale price.

The fourth and final price point is for the luxury homes. We define luxury homes as those that are worth three times the average sale price. It’s important to remember that luxury homes, like entry-level homes, are defined differently for each market.

“There are four price points in any market.”

If you’re an agent and you specialize in entry-level and average price point homes, I suggest you diversify your real estate portfolio to include more high-end and luxury homes. This is what we teach in our Luxury Listing Specialist Certification Program. Our goal is to get you to increase the average sale price of the homes you represent and make more money by working smarter, not harder. We want you to increase your income level by 30% by adding more high-end and luxury homes.

If you have any more questions about knowing your price points or want to learn more about diversifying your portfolio, don’t hesitate to call or email me anytime.

Also, don’t forget to check out our “Luxury Listing Specialist” podcast on iTunes or Stitcher. If you’d like more information or want a shot at winning some free prizes, text “LUXE” to 72000.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/The+4+Price+Points+Of+Real+Estate+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/The+4+Price+Points+Of+Real+Estate+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are four price points in every market: entry-level homes, average price point homes, high-end homes, and luxury homes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are four price points in every market: entry-level homes, average price point homes, high-end homes, and luxury homes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The New Approach to Selling Your Luxury Listings</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/the-new-approach-to-selling-your-luxury-listings.html</link>
        
          <category>Luxury Listing Specialist</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-08 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/The+Newest+Selling+Strategy+In+Real+Estate+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we are going to talk about a different approach to getting your stale listing sold. If you have a listing that is not getting activity for whatever reason, there are two types of approaches that will help expedite the sale.

The old approach involves going back to the agent and telling them that your seller is motivated and all offers will be considered. 

The new approach is what I call the “ROS” or Reverse Offer Strategy. Here is an example of how it works in action. We recently helped an owner sell their home and went back to a buyer who had seen the home about three weeks previously but had not pulled the trigger. In real estate, time is the killer of all deals, and we knew that the home was not top of mind for the buyer or their agent. So, we went back to these buyers and made an offer to them. We ended up getting a deal together, all thanks to the ROS strategy.

Currently, we are helping an agent market a $6.5 million property out in Scottsdale. There are four interested parties, but a few of them have not been returning calls or texts for a while. Using the ROS strategy, we made each of these buyers an offer and are hopeful to get a deal done quickly.

“Not only do you get to control the sale price, but it also eliminates any lowball offers.”

Here is a hypothetical situation where the ROS strategy would work quite well. Let’s say you have a $2 million dollar listing in a market where these homes are selling at an average of 90% of their asking price. 90% of $2 million is $1.8 million. You might be able to go back to the buyer and make them an offer of $1.895 million with a $25,000 bonus to the buyer’s agent if it closes by a certain date. In essence, the seller will net $1.87 million, which is well above the 90% list-to-sale ratio. But how do you present this offer to the buyer’s agent? Here’s how that conversation will go:

“Hey there. You showed my listing previously and mentioned your client is no longer interested. Well, my client actually wants to make your client the offer and would be willing to sell the property for $1.895 million. If we can get a deal done, we would give you a $25,000 bonus on top of your commission. I wanted to let you know about this so please present it to your client and get back to us.”Do not bring up percentages with the buyer’s agent or buyer, but make sure they know the price you are giving them is lower than your list price.

This is the new way of doing things. If you have any questions for me or want to learn more about the reverse offer strategy, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email at any time. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/The+Newest+Selling+Strategy+In+Real+Estate+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/The+Newest+Selling+Strategy+In+Real+Estate+%257C+Luxury+Listing+Specialist.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The old method for selling stale listings is tired and ineffective. Here is the new strategy that you should be utilizing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The old method for selling stale listings is tired and ineffective. Here is the new strategy that you should be utilizing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Want to Be More Productive? Put Down the Smartphone</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/want-to-be-more-productive-put-down-the-smartphone.html</link>
        
          <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-19 10:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Marketing+Luxury+Group/How+To+Be+More+Productive+-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a real estate agent, a team leader, and a broker-owner, being productive is essential to getting more out of your day and helping people buy and sell more properties.

How do you be more productive, though?

The first thing you should do is plan your day out. The night before, prioritize your schedule and focus on where you need to time-block.

Your real focus, though, should be something I call “MOLO”—what you can do more of, and what you can do less of to be more productive.

“Be more productive, reclaim your focus, and put the smartphone down.”

The first thing you need to do less of is being on your smartphone. Put the smartphone down and put it on mute. According to recent studies, the average smartphone user unlocks their phone 150 times a day. Checking your phone 150 times a day to see if someone texted you takes away from your focus. It only takes 2.2 seconds to unlock your smartphone, but if you’re in the middle of doing something productive, it takes an average of 11 minutes to regain the focus you had before you let your smartphone distract you. Many times, putting your smartphone out of sight helps even more.

I recently attended a Keller Williams Luxury conference where author Amy Blankson talked about her book “The Future of Happiness” and addressed the topic of how much time our smartphones take away from us. Here are a few statistics I learned:


  77% of parents think their kids are addicted to their smartphones. As bad as that is, 41% of kids think their parents are addicted to their smartphones.
  54% of people think it’s okay to check their smartphone during dinner.
  57% of people think it’s okay to check their smartphone while they’re in the bathroom.
  33% of people think it’s okay to check their smartphone during sex (don’t ask me how they came up with that number).


If something like your smartphone is distracting you and taking your time away, you need to put it down and reclaim your focus.

Many times, broker-owners and team leaders are also more productive when they close their office door because people are not always asking them about things they can probably figure out themselves. In fact, someone once told me that they put a sign up on their door that read “Stop, think about it, and go away.”

If you want to talk more about how you can be more productive or, if you have another topic in mind you would like to see me cover, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Marketing+Luxury+Group/How+To+Be+More+Productive+-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Marketing+Luxury+Group/How+To+Be+More+Productive+-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to be more productive in your business, think about what you can do more of and what you can do less of. Start by putting down the smartphone.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to be more productive in your business, think about what you can do more of and what you can do less of. Start by putting down the smartphone.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>All Your Real Estate Photography Needs Are About to Be Met</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/all-your-real-estate-photography-needs-are-about-to-be-met.html</link>
        
          <category>Increase Business</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-19 10:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/How+To+Get+The+Best+Professional+Photography-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Professional photography is an incredibly important element in any real estate transaction, but especially when it comes to the luxury market. And today’s special guest is an absolute rockstar in the realm of real estate photography. Allow me to introduce my good friend Brad Filliponi, who is joining us all the way from Australia, where he’s been in business with his company, Boxbrownie.com, for 15 years.If you’re anything like me, Brad’s company name may have struck you as a little out there. The story behind it, though, is actually very interesting. Back in 1903, Kodak introduced the first mass-produced camera. It was called the “brownie camera.” So, this product name, combined with a reference to the product’s boxy shape, is what would come to inspire Brad’s own company name. As you might expect, Brad’s creativity extends well beyond his company name. His work is carried out with quality in mind. And Brad knows full well that when photographing homes, the quality of the photos is as important as what the photographer takes in the photo.This is why Brad recommends people look at his pre-photography checklist and prepare their homes accordingly before he comes in with his camera. Following this pre-photography checklist not only helps get homes into photo-ready shape, it also helps people improve how their property may perform during an inspection.A few simple preparations are all it takes for Brad to extract a home’s full potential from behind his camera lens. Once it’s time to take photos, Brad does so knowing that there is one major rule of thumb to keep in mind regarding real estate photography. That rule? Get people’s attention.But taking great photos isn’t all Brad and his company are capable of—they also do photo enhancement. They can make a picture taken on a cloudy day look like it was captured during blue skies, for example. They can also green up grass, remove cars from driveways, and even digitally stage a home. You can find out more about Brad’s company and enjoy any of the services they offer by visiting www.boxbrownie.com.You can also enjoy $40 free credit by using my special code by clicking here. 

“The little touches Boxbrownie.com makes to enhance home photos really add up.”

Amazing results aren’t the only thing you can expect when working with Brad and his company. The prices you pay for these services are also very reasonable. Some services, like adding blue skies to a photo, cost as low as $2. And their No.1-selling enhancement, digitally staging, costs just $32. Boxbrownie.com is truly the go-to place for all of your real estate photography needs.The little touches Boxbrownie.com makes to enhance home photos really add up. “You get one chance at a first impression,” says Brad. “You might as well make it last.”Finally, as I always say: It’s not the marketing, it’s the market. While Brad handles the photography end of things, my group and I are experts on all things luxury real estate. And you could be too. When you sign up for our certification class, you too can set yourself on the path to becoming a certified luxury listing specialist. To learn more about this, go to www.luxurylistingspecialist.com.If you have any other questions for me or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/How+To+Get+The+Best+Professional+Photography-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/How+To+Get+The+Best+Professional+Photography-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m joined by a very special guest, real estate photography rockstar Brad Filliponi of Boxbrownie.com, to talk about the role he and his company play in this industry.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m joined by a very special guest, real estate photography rockstar Brad Filliponi of Boxbrownie.com, to talk about the role he and his company play in this industry.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Statistics Agents in the Luxury Market Must Know</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/4-statistics-agents-in-the-luxury-market-must-know.html</link>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-01 05:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Marketing+Luxury+Group/4+Statistics+Every+Agent+Needs+To+Know+-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are four vital statistics that every agent needs to know when selling luxury properties.


  Understand what luxury home prices start at in your market. I know certain people define luxury properties as anything above $1 million across the board. But, this simply isn’t fair. $1 million in Silicon Valley will get you a lot less than $1 million in Iowa. That being said, you need to understand the analytics for your market. My own team and I define the luxury market as anything that is at least three times the average sale price for a given market.
  Know how many months of inventory there are for luxury homes in your market. A given area might be a seller’s market overall, but the luxury market within that area could be seeing completely different conditions. While the market in general for a certain location might have very little inventory, for example, the luxury market in that area might have 12 to 16 months of inventory. As a reminder: a buyer’s market is any market where there are seven months of inventory or more; a seller’s market is a market with inventory levels at four or fewer months; and an even market has between five and six months of inventory.
  Know what price point a buyer’s market starts at. This could be a price point above or below the threshold of the luxury market, but most markets will have a point where buyers are in control.
  Understand list-to-sale ratios.In other words, if a home is listed at $1 million and it sells for an $850,000, that would constitute a 85% list-to-sale ratio. It’s important to be informed about current list-to-sale ratios in both the luxury and general market.


“These tips will all be vital to your success with working in the luxury market.”

These tips will all be vital to your success with working in the luxury market. If you’d like more tips for getting started in luxury real estate, check out www.luxurylistingspecialist.com.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Marketing+Luxury+Group/4+Statistics+Every+Agent+Needs+To+Know+-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2018/Marketing+Luxury+Group/4+Statistics+Every+Agent+Needs+To+Know+-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to work in the luxury market, there are four key statistics you absolutely must know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to work in the luxury market, there are four key statistics you absolutely must know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Use the Season to Your Advantage: Take Your Home Photos Now</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/use-the-season-to-your-advantage-take-your-home-photos-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Business Tips</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-06 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2017/The+Importance+of+Being+Proactive+-+Chicagoland+Real+Estate+Agent-.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’d like to talk about the importance of taking photos of the outside of your house now if you’re thinking of selling in the winter or the Spring of 2018.If you want to sell your home in the spring as many sellers do, I recommend you get your exterior photos taken now while there are still some green leaves on the trees.Recently, I was contacted by a homeowner that listed with another agent in March of 2017. Their contract was up, and they were unhappy with their agent, so they interviewed me. Taking a look at the photos they’d had, I noticed they hadn’t been updated from March when they were originally taken. It was a gloomy day, and there were no leaves on the trees.Being proactive, I quickly had photos taken of the home with a drone, even though their home wasn’t going on the market right away. However, you only get one chance to make a first impression, so exterior photos are really important. If the exterior photos are drab and dreary, buyers may not want to see the photos of inside and ultimately move onto a different listing.

“You only get one chance to make a first impression, so exterior photos are really important”

If your home isn’t currently on the market, or if it is but you plan to make changes to your listing, be proactive. Interview your agents now, and take your photos now. I talk about this among many other things in my new book “Luxury Listing Specialist”. This fall we attended many conferences where we were rubbing elbows with some of the top agents from around the world, so I could come back to my marketplace to serve my clients more effectively with cutting-edge marketing, both online and offline.If you need a second opinion on your real estate transaction, you’re thinking of selling, or you have any real estate questions at all, please reach out to us. Let’s keep up the momentum and finish 2017 strong.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2017/The+Importance+of+Being+Proactive+-+Chicagoland+Real+Estate+Agent-.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2017/The+Importance+of+Being+Proactive+-+Chicagoland+Real+Estate+Agent-.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Being proactive is a key element to getting the right photos to sell your home. Don’t wait until it’s gloomy and dreary outside. Do it now.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Being proactive is a key element to getting the right photos to sell your home. Don’t wait until it’s gloomy and dreary outside. Do it now.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using Art to Market Luxury Homes</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/using-art-to-market-luxury-homes.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Business Tips</category>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-21 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2017/Using+Art+to+Market+Luxury+Homes+-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In the video above which is geared more towards real estate agents, you will see an amazing property that we are marketing right now at just under $3 million. It has some amazing features such as an indoor saltwater pool, but we wanted to make these features pop on camera and video.

To do that, we decided to showcase some amazing artwork from IKONICK, and these big canvas portraits are all over the property catching the eyes of buyers and their agents.  This artwork company took several professional photo’s and leveraged those photo’s on social media which lead to an online spike in activity for this particular home.

“As you can see, the artwork is visually stunning.”

As you can see, the art is visually stunning. Time is money, and with marketing like this, we decrease the time a luxury home spends on the market before selling. Adding this beautiful art to an already beautiful home really brings it all together and shows prospective buyers the unique features of the home by tying in the artwork.

As we’ve seen time and time again, marketing your luxury home properly will lead to more offers, higher offers, and a quicker sale. It might take a bit of an investment, but that investment will be worth it when the deal is closed and you no longer have to worry about selling or even maintaining the property.

If you have any questions for me about how to successfully market your home for sale, don’t hesitate to give me a call or sending me an email. I would love to hear from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2017/Using+Art+to+Market+Luxury+Homes+-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2017/Using+Art+to+Market+Luxury+Homes+-+Chicagoland+Luxury+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Marketing luxury homes is a different animal entirely. Here’s one of our newest techniques that has been seeing great results.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Marketing luxury homes is a different animal entirely. Here’s one of our newest techniques that has been seeing great results.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can Matched Pairs Tell Us About Resale Value When Selling A Home?</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/what-can-matched-pairs-tell-us-about-resale-value-when-selling-a-home.html</link>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-09 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2017/What+Can+Matched+Pairs+Tell+Us+About+Home+Value%253F+-+Chicagoland+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Matched pairs is a term you probably haven’t heard of. If you’re thinking of selling your home, it’s always wise to consider making improvements and upgrades.  However, you’ve got to know where to spend your money in order to get the highest possible return. Recently, I had a client who spent about $20,000 on leaf guards that were nice but didn’t really add any value to his home. 

The first thing to do when selling your home is to consult a professional like myself who knows what they’re doing. That being said, it’s always best to do a few cosmetic improvements at least. For unique properties or properties where there aren’t a lot of comparables, we recommend an appraisal prior to going on the market as well.

I work with one of the best appraisers in the Midwest, and he recently put together a thorough report about matched pairs. He wrote a report that compared five properties to five similar properties. That brings us back to the term matched pairs. These “matched pairs” were then compared to each other.

“”

Half of the properties had minimal fixes. The other half were situations where the owner put in a significant amount of money to improve the home before selling. Some of the owners put in as much as $25,000.

The homes that had money put in to make significant improvements ended up selling a lot quicker and for a lot more money.  Some owners invested $25,000 and ended up selling the home for $50,000 more than the owner who only put $5,000 into their home. A lot of those homes that weren’t invested in too much probably sat on the market for quite a while due to price adjustments.

If you have any questions for me or you’re thinking of putting your home on the market anytime soon, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2017/What+Can+Matched+Pairs+Tell+Us+About+Home+Value%253F+-+Chicagoland+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mike+LaFido/Videos/2017/What+Can+Matched+Pairs+Tell+Us+About+Home+Value%253F+-+Chicagoland+Real+Estate+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Home improvements are important before selling. These numbers tell the truth about how much you should invest.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Home improvements are important before selling. These numbers tell the truth about how much you should invest.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The New Age of Real Estate Marketing</title>
        <link>luxeredefined.com/the-new-age-of-real-estate-marketing.html</link>
        
        <author>Michael LaFido</author>
        <pubDate>2015-08-19 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Lifestyle is very important when you sell home - but what exactly does that mean?

The traditional marketing method of putting pictures of homes online just isn’t going to cut it anymore. Videos bring a whole new dimension to the selling process, but only 2% of agents are using it to market homes! Of that 2%, NONE OF THEM use lifestyle videos like we do.

Most agents, if they’re using videos, are only posting YouTube videos made up of a succession of still photographs. Recently, we just broke the record for the highest sale price in Wheaton history because we take marketing to another level. Before we came along, the home sat on the market for an entire year and had the price reduced by as much as half a million dollars. Once we got the listing, we sold the home for record price in only 79 days!

So, how did lifestyle marketing get this home sold? The truth is only 10% of buyers can visualize whereas 90% of people can only see the home as it is. This is why staging is so crucial in real estate nowadays. But lifestyle marketing goes beyond just staging; it’s all about accentuating the best features of the home to show the buyer all the opportunities the property affords.

If you have any questions about lifestyle marketing, or if you need real estate assistance of any kind, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re always here to make your real estate dreams a reality!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="luxeredefined.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Chicagoland Real Estate Expert discusses how current real estate trends are doing in the local area.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Michael LaFido</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Chicagoland Real Estate Expert discusses how current real estate trends are doing in the local area.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Marketing Luxury Listings, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Michael LaFido</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Michael LaFido</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Marketing Luxury Group - your professional Marketing Luxury Listings Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
